Aaron **Goidel Computer Science Student**

github.com/AaronCGoidel

□ (973) 747-2462 @ acgoidel@gmail.com

♀ Montclair, NJ

Creative and driven computer science student with loves for learning and problem solving. Experience working in teams creating new technologies; strong leadership and presentations skills, and equally strong technical ability. Interested in machine learning, operating systems, and in working to apply computer science to areas of passion, such as law, food, and music, in new ways.



PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

June 2019 August 2019

Cybersecurity Research Intern | NATIONAL SECURITY AGENCY

Fort Meade, MD

- > Authored a patch in the Linux operating system, implementing a security hook and permissions for controlling file system watches, including corresponding test suite
- > Experimented with machine learning models to estimate the proximity of Bluetooth Low Energy enabled IoT devices in obstructed spaces
- > Presented progress and findings to groups of researchers in technical briefings

C Python SELinux Machine Learning Bluetooth LE Cybersecurity

November 2016 August 2017

Lead Coding Instructor | MONTCLAIR LEARNING CENTER

Montclair, NJ

- > Taught coding in after school and summer programs to primary and middle school aged students
- > Created and executed lesson plans in Scratch, App Inventor, and Python
- > Interfaced with parents on a weekly basis about student's progress
- > Oversaw work done by junior employees

Scratch Python Teaching



EDUCATION

September 2019 | Current Student | UNIVERSITY OF TORONTO

Current

- > Current second year student seeking a Bachelor of Science in Computer Science with minors in Pure Mathematics and Linguistics
- > GPA: 3.97/4.00
- > 2019-2020 Dean's List
- > Expected graduation: Spring 2023
- > Member of the Mathematics and Computer Science Society

June 2019

September 2015 | High School | MONTCLAIR KIMBERLEY ACADEMY

- > Graduated with a GPA of 3.75/4.0
 - > Classes included: AP Physics C, AP Calculus AB, AP Computer Science A, AP Chinese, Data Structures and Algorithms
 - > Leadership roles in several organizations including: Mock Trial (lead lawyer and captain), STEM Team (president), School Newspaper (chief digital editor), Committee for Educational Technology



TECHNICAL SKILLS

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES C, Python, JavaScript (NodeJS, React, React Native), Java

PLATFORMS & TECHNOLOGIES Git (GitHub), Unix Command Line, LaTeX

SPOKEN LANGUAGES English (native), Mandarin (intermediate)

***** CERTIFICATIONS

U.S. TOP SECRET//SI//TK SECURITY CLEARANCE Including full-scope background investigation, polygraph examination, and psychological evaluation

APPLE CERTIFIED MAC TECHNICIAN

RED CROSS CPR/AED CERTIFIED

T Honors, Awards, and Achievements

2017, 2018, 2019 Lockheed Martin Code Quest competition champion (New Jersey, Advanced Division)

2016, 2017, 2018 Agile Youth Hackathon champion

2019 Montclair Kimberley Academy commencement award in Computer Science

2018 Essex County Mock Trial champion

PROJECTS

SAFESEND

github.com/MKA-Stem/ayc-galvanize

SafeSend utilizes two-factor-authentication and multi-layer encryption to generate secure links to data, ensuring it is only accessible by the intended recipient

JavaScript ReactJS NodeJS Twillio

FSNOTIFY LSM HOOK

☑ Patch on git.kernel.org/

Implemented a new security check to Security-Enhanced Linux and the Linux Kernel which adds fine-grained control over the setting of watches on file system objects

C | SELinux | Kernel | Linux Security Module

COOKIE

Combining my passions for computer science and food, Cookie is a native smartphone app which applies graph theory to recipes, resulting in a dynamic cookbook. By treating recipes as a dependency graph, instead of as a static block of text, Cookie can combine, and simplify recipes to maximize efficiency in the kitchen

React Native Typescript Graph Theory Mobile App